<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>CS-Notes</title>
      <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on CS-Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Datadog APM</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/Datadog/Datadog-APM</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/Datadog/Datadog-APM</guid>
    <description>Abstract § Application Performance Monitoring (APM) Serverless Setup § The example below is based on ECS Fargate The entire setup is around Task Definition Pipe application log to AWS Firelens § Add the following block to Task Definition inside the application container block Update the heightened parts with your own values &quot;logConfiguration&quot;: { &quot;logDriver&quot;: &quot;awsfirelens&quot;, &quot;options&quot;: { &quot;Host&quot;: &quot;http-intake.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 03:30:30 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>ECS</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/AWS/Compute/ECS/ECS</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/AWS/Compute/ECS/ECS</guid>
    <description>Abstract § A lightweight container orchestration service We can mount Volume to it for data that can be lost when Container is terminated Components § Container § We can obtain a shell into it using ECS Exec Obtain Private IP of the container Must have curl &amp;&amp; jq (JSON Processor) containerPrivateIP=$(curl $ECS_CONTAINER_METADATA_URI | jq -r &#039;.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 02:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Application Performance Monitoring (APM)</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Software-Engineering/Monitoring/Application-Performance-Monitoring-(APM)</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Software-Engineering/Monitoring/Application-Performance-Monitoring-(APM)</guid>
    <description>Abstract § Collect Trace from backend &amp; database for all the incoming API Requests Deep visibility into applications with out-of-the-box performance dashboards for web services, queues, and databases to monitor requests, errors and latency .</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 02:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Datadog RUM</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/Datadog/Datadog-RUM</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/Datadog/Datadog-RUM</guid>
    <description>Abstract § Real User Monitoring Enable us to get the metadata about the client such as the user-agent, IP Address &amp; record down the user actions on the page in a video format Setup § The example below is based on next.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 02:00:03 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Interrupts (中断)</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/OS/Main-Components/Process-Related/Interrupts-(%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%AD)/Interrupts-(%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%AD)</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/OS/Main-Components/Process-Related/Interrupts-(%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%AD)/Interrupts-(%E4%B8%AD%E6%96%AD)</guid>
    <description>Abstract § When an interrupt occurs, Program Counter jumps to Interrupt Handler (Interrupt Service Routine, ISR) &amp; execute 2 forms - Signal (Software Interrupt) &amp; Hardware interrupts (外中断) Benefits § We don’t need to get CPU to keep Polling for response which may take a long time to produce.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 15:51:21 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Integer Encoding (数字编码)</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Computer-Organisation/Number-System/Integer-Encoding-(%E6%95%B0%E5%AD%97%E7%BC%96%E7%A0%81)</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Computer-Organisation/Number-System/Integer-Encoding-(%E6%95%B0%E5%AD%97%E7%BC%96%E7%A0%81)</guid>
    <description>Abstract § There are 3 Variants, computer use the 2’s Complement (补码) variant to store integer Computers use 2’s Complement (补码) to store the integers, since it solves the flaws in Sign-and-Magnitude (原码) and 1’s Complement (反码) Below is a 4-bits Integer Encoding under the 3 Variants 3 Variants § Sign-and-Magnitude (原码) § Represent positive and negative decimal integers in binary with the help of Sign Bit Divide the number of bits into 2 parts, one part for negative number, another part for positive number Require extra Logic Gates The Adder logic gates cant be used for subtraction This can be avoided using 1’s Complement (反码) or 2’s Complement (补码) 1’s Complement (反码) § For negative number, all bits are inverted except the Sign Bit which is 1 and positive number unchanged We can invert all bits except Sign Bit to obtain Sign-and-Magnitude (原码) Reuse Logic Gates We re-can use Adder logic gates, without building extra logic circuit like a subtraction logic gates Mathematically wrong definition of 0 We have +0 (when all bits are 0) &amp; -0(when all bits are 1) under this encoding, this can be solved by 2’s Complement (补码) 2’s Complement (补码) § This builds on top of 1’s Complement (反码), the only difference is to add extra 1 to the negative number in 1’s Complement (反码) to have only 1 binary encoding for 0 We can calculate the decimal value by taking the value Sign Bit (negative) and perform addition with value of Magnitude (all are positive) Terminologies § Sign Bit § The first bit from left 0 denotes positive 1 denotes negative Magnitude § All the bits in the encoding except Sign Bit Reference § Sign-and-Magnitude Addition and Subtraction Hello-Algo .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 15:38:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Problem Solving</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Problem-solving/Problem-Solving</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Problem-solving/Problem-Solving</guid>
    <description>Abstract § Systematic way of solving a given problem 9 Tips § 1. Use the defining features of the set-up § Look at what is given Ask the definition of each term How the ideas piece up together (infer) Example 1: Approaching a problem related to Circle, Inscribed Angle Theorem.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 15:14:54 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Dockerfile</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/Docker/3-Components/Dockerfile/Dockerfile</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/Docker/3-Components/Dockerfile/Dockerfile</guid>
    <description>Abstract § Set of steps for Docker to build Docker Container Keywords § ENV § Set the Environment Variable in the Docker Container .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 11:58:31 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Docker Build</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/Docker/Docker-Build</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/Docker/Docker-Build</guid>
    <description>Abstract § Convert Dockerfile to Docker Container Cautions § —build-arg § Used to pass dynamic values to Engine for the building process Not Environment Variable, that is set with [[Dockerfile#env|ENV]] Frontend Build § Needs the Environment Variable at the container build stage only, not when the container is running .</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 11:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Configuration File, Vault</title>
    <link>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/HashiCorp-Vault/Main-Components/Configuration-File,-Vault</link>
    <guid>https://notes.yxy.ninja/Tools/HashiCorp-Vault/Main-Components/Configuration-File,-Vault</guid>
    <description>#vault Config file for HashiCorp Vault. Contains different keywords to tune the behaviour of the vault like what storage backend to use &amp; how to unseal the vault etc Some of the config can be done using the specific Environment Variable Can be written in either JSON or HCL Some networking related setting can be set dynamically using go-sockaddr template TCP Listener Example [cluster_address,api_addr] Example Example Production Configuration File seal § # Below is using AWS KMS for [[Auto Unseal]] seal &quot;awskms&quot; { region = &quot;ap-southeast-1&quot; kms_key_id = &quot;5b2b78c8-c4db-43d9-ba6b-73295f2ec154&quot; } Example vault.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 11:48:16 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>